Shubham Kumar Gupta

Pune, India **\(+91-8899654510** shubham_gupta@myyahoo.com in linkedin.com/in/-skg

Profile Summary

Experienced Data Engineer and Tech Lead with a demonstrated history of working in the information technology and services industry. Proficient in Python, PySpark, and Google Cloud Platform (GCP) with extensive experience in ETL pipeline development, data migration, and machine learning model pre-training. Recognized for exceptional problem-solving skills, teamwork, and communication abilities.

Work Experience

March 2024 - Present • Tech Lead, HCL Seeking opportunities/projects in various domains.

• Senior Data Engineer, LTIMindtree Jan 2023 - Dec 2023 Developed ETL pipelines and data migration jobs using Python, PySpark, GCP, Apache Beam, Airflow, Azure Data Factory, Databricks, SQL, and MongoDB. Worked on a project for Procter & Gamble.

Various Roles, Tata Consultancy Services

Jan 2019 - Jan 2023

- Jan 2019 June 2020 Python Developer, PWC Developed tools and web scraping scripts, generated reports using Python, Linux, Shell scripting, Batch scripting, and SQL.
- o GCP Data Engineer, Ingram Micro July 2020 - Feb 2021 Migrated data to Google Cloud using Apache Beam, Python, SQL, and GCP. Developed a tool to translate Oracle DDLs to BigQuery DDL using Python.
- Senior Software Developer, Google March 2021 - Jan 2023 Worked with Google Document AI in pre-training models and testing performance. Assisted clients with data migration and data engineering tasks using Python, PySpark, Apache Beam, Airflow, Vertex AI, Document AI, SQL, Pandas, Kafka, etc.

Education

B.Tech in Electronics and Communication Engineering UPTU, Lucknow

Skills

• Technical Skills: Python, PySpark, Google Cloud, • Soft Skills: Communication, Creativity, Teamwork, SQL, Apache Beam, Azure Data Factory, Apache Kafka, Apache Airflow

Problem-Solving, Time-Management, Customer-Focus

Honors & Awards

Bright Student Award, Government of India

Aug 2011

• Team Player Award, LTIMindtree

Jul 2023

• Employee of the Year, Tata Consultancy Services

Mar 2020